Guide to the James E. Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson Papers TAM 347
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series XVII. Audiocassettes. (Oral History Collection 57) NOTE: This series is stored with the Library's Oral History collections.
  - Subseries XVII:B: Lectures, Speeches
    - Party Theory, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 219)
    - Party Theory, Party School, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 220)
    - Party Theory, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 221)
    - Party / Youth, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 222)
    - Side 1: Party; Side 2: United Front (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 223)
    - Party / Youth (8), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 224)
    - Paul Robeson Commemoration - New Zealand's Tribute, Aug 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 225)
    - Peace History of the Party's Position on African-American Equality, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 226)
    - Peace Workshop, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 227)
    - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 228)
    - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (3), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 229)
    - Side 1: Weinstock, L.: Trade Unione Movement, Bio - Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois; Side 2: Jackson, J.: Petty Burgeois Nationalism (1), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 230)
    - Petty Burgeois Nationalism (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 231)
    - Philosophy, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 232)
    - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 233)
    - Philosophy (2), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 234)
    - Philosophy (3), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 235)
    - Philosophy, Oct 1982 (Box OH57, Folder 236)
    - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Dialectical Materialism, Oct 1982 (Box OH57, Folder 237)
    - Philosophy / Dialectical MaterialismNational School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 238)
    - Philosophy, Dialectics (4), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 239)
    - Philosophical Falsifiers (2)AYD Reports, TM Report, Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 240)
    - Philosophical Falsifiers (3), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 241)
    - Political Economy, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 242)
    - Political Economy, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 243)
    - Political Economy (3-4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 244)
    - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Inflation, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 245)
    - Side 1: Political Economy / Inflation; Side 2: Socialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 246)
    - Political Economy, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 247)
    - Political Economy, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 248)
    - Political Economy, Commodity ProductionLecture and Afterword Session, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 249)
    - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Accumulation of the Capital, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 250)
    - Side 1: Lumer, Hy: Monetary Crisis; Side 2: Jackson, James: Political Economy Review (2), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 251)
    - Political Economy, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 252)
    - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Questioning Students, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 253)
    - Political Economy, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 254)
    - Political Economy, Jul 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 255)
    - Political Economy (1), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 256)
    - Political Economy (2), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 257)
    - Political Economy (3), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 258)
    - Political Economy, Questions on (3), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 259)
    - Political Economy, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 260)
    - Political Economy, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 261)
    - Political Economy (final), Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 262)
    - Politics and Revolution (2)National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 263)
    - Portland, Maine Radio, Oct 1986 (Box OH57, Folder 264)
    - Side 1: Principles of Party Organization and Functioning; Side 2: Industrial Concentration, Feb 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 265)
    - Q&A On Children; Soviet Prophet, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 266)
    - Questions and Report from GRPS, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 267)
    - Questions for James E. Jackson, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 268)
    - Racism (5-6?), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 269)
    - Side 1: Racism; Side 2: Cont'd + Q&A's, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 270)
    - Racism, Fight Against, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 271)
    - Side 1: Racism with Mike Welch; Side 2: Party Organization with Mike Welch, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 272)
    - Report back from Workshops (Jackson, J.; Meyers, G.), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 273)
    - Report on 60th Anniversary of Soviet Union, Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 274)
    - Report on Trip to China, Jul 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 275)
    - Revolution Process / Components of Revolution, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 276)
    - Revolutionary Conditions, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 277)
    - School Evaluation (1), Feb 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 278)
    - School Evaluation (2), Feb 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 279)
    - School Graduation, Closing Speech, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 280)
    - Situation of Black Americans, May 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 281)
    - Social Economics 2/12, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 282)
    - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Discussion and Reports 2/28, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 283)
    - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Questions on Political Economy, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 284)
    - Socialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 285)
    - Side 1: Socialism; Side 2: Lenin, the Party, Style in Leadership, Mar 1973 (Box OH57, Folder 286)
    - On Socialism (3), May 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 287)
    - On Socialism (4), May 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 288)
    - Socialism and Communism (1), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 289)
    - Socialism and the Soviet Union, Aug 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 290)
    - Socialist Convention / Unemployment (4), May 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 291)
    - Socialist Revolution, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 292)
    - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (1), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 293)
    - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 294)
    - Soviet Union, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 295)
    - Soviet Union, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 296)
    - Soviet Union, Jul 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 297)
    - On the Soviet Union Berlin Conference, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 298)
    - Staff Seminar Discussion, May 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 299)
    - Side 1: The State; Side 2: Q&A, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 300)
    - The State, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 301)
    - The State, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 302)
    - Steel Strikes (?) and Socialism, Jul 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 303)
    - Side 1: Strategy; Side 2: United Front, Tactics, Sectarianism with M. Welch, S. Douglas, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 304)
    - Strategy and Tactics (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 305)
    - Side 1: Strategy and Tactics; Side 2: Irish Struggles, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 306)
    - Strategy and Tactics, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 307)
    - Strategy and Tactics with Gus Hall, Apr 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 308)
    - Side 1: On Strategy and Tactics / Introduction of L. Dlugan; Side 2: Dlugan, Lee: Monopoly Prices and Profits, Imperialism / Historical, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 309)
    - Suslov, In Memorial To, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 310)
    - Side 1: Theory of Knowledge; Side 2: Blank, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 311)
    - Trade Union, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 312)
    - Side 1: Trade Union (White; Jackson, J.); Side 2: Woman Question(White; Jackson, J.), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 313)
    - Side 1: Trade Union; Side 2: National Question, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 314)
    - Trade Union Meeting or Conference, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 315)
    - Transition to Social Revolution and Left Center, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 316)
    - Trotsky, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 317)
    - Trotskyism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 318)
    - United Front, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 319)
    - United Front (2-3), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 320)
    - United Front (3-4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 321)
    - Side 1: United Front; Side 2: The YWLL (Young Workers' Liberation League), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 322)
    - Urgent Tasks in Fight for PeaceCentral Committee Report, Nov 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 323)
    - VALB Socialist Scholars ConferenceWorkshop includes: Wellman, Saul, Apr 1994 (Box OH57, Folder 324)
    - Washington, Feb 1980 (Box OH57, Folder 325)
    - WBA I - J. Jackson with Bogdan Denitsch, Jan 1982 (Box OH57, Folder 326)
    - W.E.B. Du Bois Memorial Lecture, Boston, Mar 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 327)
    - W.E.B. Du Bois: Our Black Titan, Washington, D.C., Feb 1973 (Box OH57, Folder 328)
    - West Berlin, Jan 1984 (Box OH57, Folder 329)
    - Women's Equality (3-4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 330)
    - Women's Question, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 331)
    - Women's Question (1) with J. Teixeira, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 332)
    - Women's Question (2), Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 333)
    - Women's Question (3), Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 334)
    - Working Class History of the Nationalities Wheel (?)22nd Convention, Aug 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 335)
    - World Peace CouncilMedal Ceremony for J. Jackson, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 336)
  - Subseries XVII:C: Speeches by Others
    - Bert, Erik: Communist International, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 337)
    - Brodine, M. J.: Asians in America, Feb 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 338)
    - Chandra, Romesh: World Peace Council, Jan 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 339)
    - Dennis, Ellen with O. Harrington, P. Miriam: Berlin, Nov 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 340)
    - Diskin, Louis and Others, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 341)
    - Fitzgerald, Albert: About Himself and about the Unions, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 342)
    - Hall, Gus: Side 1: PA Political Union; Side 2: Boston Conference, Nov 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 343)
    - Hall, Gus: Main Address, N.C., Jan 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 344)
    - Hall, Gus: On Greece + Q&A's, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 345)
    - Hall, Gus: Update, Aug 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 346)
    - Hall, Gus: Update, Nov 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 347)
    - Hall, Gus: Update, Jan 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 348)
    - Hall, Gus: Update, Feb 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 349)
    - Side 1: Hall, Gus Update; Side 2: J. Jackson, Jul 1990 (Box OH57, Folder 350)
    - Hudson, Hosea, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 351)
    - Lipschutz, Joan; Jacques, Jeff, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 352)
    - Mobhito, Moses: General Secretary, C.P. South Africa, Mar 28, 1968 (?) (Box OH57, Folder 353)
    - Mobhito, Moses; Mullens, Leith; Diskin, Louis, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 354)
    - Side 1: Mora, Grace; Side 2: Winston, Henry, Skit of Students, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 355)
    - Patrinos, Sandy: Strategy and Tactics: Party School, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 356)
    - Shelby: Female Conflicts, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 357)
    - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (2), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 358)
    - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (3), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 359)
    - Side 1: Storey, Rasheed / Afternoon Plenary; Side 2: Afternoon Plenary, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 360)
    - Tyner, Jarvis: Political Report, Mar 1987 (Box OH57, Folder 361)
    - Winston, Henry: Communist Party, Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 362)
    - Winston, Henry: School Opening, Feb 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 363)
    - Winston, Henry Speech (3), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 364)
    - Winston, Henry: Party Theory (3), Party School, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 365)
    - Unknown Speaker (man): Class Struggle, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 366)
    - Unknown Speaker (man)Communist Unity, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 367)
    - Unknown Speaker(s): Discussion on an event at Carnegie Hall, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 368)
    - Unknown speaker (woman): Labor Union and the Party, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 369)
    - Unknown speaker (woman): Martin Luther King, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 370)
    - Unknown speakers: Political Economy - Student Session, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 371)
    - Unknown speakers: Students' Discussions and Presentations on Capitalism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 372)
  - Subseries XVII:D: 7 inch reel of 1/4 inch-wide Recording Tapes
    - Patsu, Kofi and other unknown speakers: Young Farmers Rally at Kunnasi Chance, Mar 1965 (Box OH57, Folder 373)